<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Smart Cities | Antonela Tommasel</title>
    <link>https://tommantonela.github.io/tags/smart-cities/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tommantonela.github.io/tags/smart-cities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Smart Cities</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Smart Cities</title>
      <link>https://tommantonela.github.io/tags/smart-cities/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Deep Learning model for estimating parking space availability</title>
      <link>https://tommantonela.github.io/publication/2021jccc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tommantonela.github.io/publication/2021jccc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Smart Cities to Social Cities: Smart Cities at the Service of Social Good</title>
      <link>https://tommantonela.github.io/talk/wids_kfump2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tommantonela.github.io/talk/wids_kfump2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract-&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: justify&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Today, 55 percent of the world’s population lives in urban areas, a proportion that is expected to increase to 68 percent by 2050.” – United Nations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence has the potential to help improving many aspects of the daily life. In this context, making cities smarter is the challenge of the new era, which brings together aspects of computer sciences, physics, operations research, management science, decision sciences, economics and the social sciences. With the large amount of data available from diverse sources and the advance in technology, new opportunities to address the fundamental (and perhaps social) problems of cities, citizens and society arise. But this is not an individual effort. The more cities that are working toward the greater good, the more prosperous cities and citizens will be as a whole. In this talk we will explore how the data harnessed from cities can be applied to the social good. Then, we will focus on good practices for developing our solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Citizens</title>
      <link>https://tommantonela.github.io/project/digital-citizenship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tommantonela.github.io/project/digital-citizenship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: justify&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awarded by UNICEN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PI: Antonela Tommasel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Democracy and formal political processes depend fundamentally on effective communication and
informed decision-making on public issues. The development of digital technologies, the expansion
of the Internet and the growth of social networks have generated profound changes in political
forms at a global level, modifying the bases of citizen participation. These new technologies have
been established as a new way to channel and facilitate citizen participation in a given territory,
offering new communication tools with government entities and their authorities. EParticipation
involves the use of the information and communication technologies, mainly Internet, as the means
of participation in democratic and consultative social processes. The goal of eParticipation is to
support active citizenship with the latest technological developments, increasing access and the
possibility of participating, and promoting a government that is open and close to citizens.
Considering that democratic systems favour the interests of large groups of citizens, the more voices
supporting a political proposal, the greater their chances of success. However, achieving effective
citizen participation is a challenge, given that the simple fact of having access to online services does
not imply the willingness of citizens to participate. In this context, social media sites could have a
preponderant role in terms of citizen participation, making individuals not only feel that they have
access to the information directly and permanently, but also the right to be involved in the public
discourse and decisions. Consequently, it is necessary to carry out studies for determining the
current status and perspectives of citizen participation in the context of social media. Thereby, this
project aims to study and characterize the relationship between digital citizens and government
entities in social media, in the context of eParticipation, to enable the definition of practices and
strategies that lead to the efficient use of social media for communication between public
institutions and citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
